KEITH CHEW

keithchewzk@gmail.com | https://kippsss.github.io/heyitskeith | https://www.linkedin.com/in/keith-chew-36745a1ba/

PROFILE

I am an aspiring AI/Software Engineer currently in MSD's Emerging Talent Rotation program, which allows me to work with three different teams over two years. My experience spans AI, cloud infrastructure, web development, and CI/CD pipelines. As I'm early in my career, I'm eager to gain diverse experiences in the technology field.

EXPERIENCE

AI Engineer at MSD

Jul 2024 - Present

- Developed feature enhancements for MSD's enterprise GenAI products.
- Enabled users to contextualise prompts using internal company data through prompt engineering, orchestration, and RAG.
- Built product backend CI pipeline to streamline code testing and scanning capabilities.

Prompt Eng. | RAG | Python | FastAPI | CI

Software Engineer at MSD

Jan 2024 – Jun 2024

- Full-stack development for an enterprise short link management tool with Next.js, TypeScript, and AWS.
- Mobile frontend development for a leadership skills application with React Native.
- Engaged in product discovery by conducting user interviews to inform design and development decisions.

Next.js | TypeScript | React Native | AWS

Cloud Engineer at MSD

Jul 2023 - Dec 2023

- Developed AWS architectures to streamline internal reporting, ensuring precise resource cost allocation, with services such as Lambda, DynamoDB, S3, SQS, Glue, etc.
- Data transformation initiatives as part of a larger project migrating users to dedicated AWS accounts to improve cost accountability for enterprise applications.
- Migration of team's cloud resources to Terraform following company movement towards IaC adoption.
- Created dashboards for application owners to view and self-manage cloud spending practices in their teams.
- Certified for AWS Cloud Practitioner

Python | AWS | Solution Architecture | SQL

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Computational Biology at National University of Singapore

Aug 2019 - May 2023

Graduated with Honours (Distinction)

Bioinformatics | NLP | Data Science | Databases | AI/ML | Genomics | Big Data

REFERENCES

Parita Sanghani

Engineering Manager, Hyperautomation & AI, MSD | parita.sanghani@msd.com

Ashley Lee

Product Manager, Central Software Engineering, MSD | ashley.lee@msd.com

Florencia Wijaya

Product Manager, Cloud Business Office, MSD | florencia.tiffany.wijaya@msd.com